Cook, Alice Papers /3012
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series Series VI: Subject Files
  - Sub-Series D. Comparable Worth
    - Trade Unions- Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) (Box 83, Folder 13)
    - Trade Unions-Communications Workers (Box 83, Folder 14)
    - Trade Unions - IUE (Box 83, Folder 15)
    - Trade Unions-SEIU (Box 83, Folder 16-17)
    - Trade Unions-UE (Box 83, Folder 18)
    - Universities (Box 83, Folder 19)
    - Universities-Yale (Box 83, Folder 20)
    - Wage Discrimination (Box 83, Folder 21)
    - Wages-Trade Unions (Box 83, Folder 22)
    - Washington State (Box 83, Folder 23)
    - Wisconsin (Box 83, Folder 24)
  - Sub-Series E. Comparative Studies
    - Abortion, 1975-1990 (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Africa, 1994-1996 (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Asia, 1987-1996 (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Austria, 1967 (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Bangladesh, 1980 (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Bias, 1995 (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - Bibliography, 1975-1986 (Box 84, Folder 7-10)
    - Birth Control, 1975 (Box 84, Folder 11)
    - European Women's Center for Studies in a Changing Society (CEFRES), 1979 (Box 84, Folder 12)
    - Child Care, 1968-1996 (Box 84, Folder 13-21)
    - Comparable Worth, 1989-1994 (Box 84, Folder 22)
    - Comparative Education, 1974 (Box 84, Folder 23)
    - Copenhagen, 1979-1980 (Box 84, Folder 24-27)
    - Demographic Data, 1971-1997 (Box 84, Folder 28-32)
    - Developing Countries, 1985 (Box 84, Folder 33)
    - Discrimination, 1973-1993 (Box 84, Folder 34-38)
    - Divorce, 1975 (Box 84, Folder 39)
    - EC (Council of Europe) - Economics, 1997 (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - EC - Equality, 1989 (Box 85, Folder 2-3)
    - ECC, 1970-1975 (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - ECC, 1975-1980 (Box 85, Folder 5-9)
    - ECC, 1980-1984 (Box 85, Folder 10-16)
    - ECC, 1985-1989 (Box 85, Folder 17-21)
    - ECC, 1990-1991 (Box 86, Folder 1-3)
    - ECC, 1992 (Box 86, Folder 4-7)
    - EU-Court, 1996 (Box 86, Folder 8)
    - EU-Family/Children, 1996 (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - EU-Hours, 1997 (Box 86, Folder 10)
    - EU-Structure, 1995-1996 (Box 86, Folder 11)
    - EU-Taxation, 1997 (Box 86, Folder 12)
    - Eastern Europe, 1994-1997 (Box 86, Folder 13)
    - Eastern Europe-Economy, 1994-1997 (Box 86, Folder 14)
    - Education, 1974 (Box 86, Folder 15)
    - Education of Women, 1976-1994 (Box 86, Folder 16-17)
    - Education-Vocational Training, 1978-1992 (Box 86, Folder 18-21)
    - Employment, 1971 (Box 86, Folder 22)
    - Equal Pay, 1972-1997 (Box 86, Folder 23-25)
    - Equality, 1975-1997 (Box 86, Folder 26-29)
    - Family, 1971-1996 (Box 86, Folder 30-33)
    - Family-Child Labor, 1996 (Box 86, Folder 34)
    - Family-Maternity, 1997 (Box 86, Folder 35)
    - Foreign Workers, 1983-1991 (Box 86, Folder 36)
    - Future, 1986 (Box 86, Folder 37)
    - General, 1966-1979 (Box 86, Folder 38-41)
    - General, 1985 (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - General, 1980-1982 (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - General, 1982-1983 (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - General, 1975-1978 (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - General, 1978-1979 (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - General, 1991-1997 (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Glass Ceiling (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Globalization, 1997 (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Health and Safety, 1971-1992 (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - Health and Safety, 1987-1992 (Box 87, Folder 10)
    - History, 1980-1996 (Box 87, Folder 11)
    - Hours of Work, 1978-1984 (Box 87, Folder 12)
    - Hours of Work, 1990-1993 (Box 87, Folder 13)
    - Hours of Work, 1989 (Box 87, Folder 14)
    - Hours of Work, 1986-1991 (Box 87, Folder 15)
    - Household work, 1980-1990 (Box 87, Folder 16)
    - Human Rights, 1993 (Box 87, Folder 17)
    - Industrial Health, 1974 (Box 87, Folder 18)
    - Integration, 1997 (Box 87, Folder 19)
    - Int'l. Ind. Relation Assn., 1986-1989 (Box 87, Folder 20)
    - Int'l. Lab. Office, 1970-1985 (Box 87, Folder 21)
    - Int'l. Labor Office, 1977 (Box 87, Folder 22)
    - Int'l. Labor Office, 1990-1996 (Box 87, Folder 23)
    - Int'l. Labor Office, 1970-1975 (Box 87, Folder 24)
    - Int'l. Lab. Off., 1973-1974 (Box 87, Folder 25)
    - Int'l. Metal Wkrs. Fed., 1973 (Box 87, Folder 26)
    - Int'l. Women Wkrs. Conf., 1959 (Box 87, Folder 27)
    - Int'l. Women's Year, 1975 (Box 87, Folder 28)
    - Int'l. Women's Year - Mexico City, 1975-1986 (Box 87, Folder 29)
    - Int'l. Women's Year - Mexico City, 1974-1975 (Box 87, Folder 30)
    - Islam, 1997 (Box 87, Folder 31)
    - Japan, 1994 (Box 87, Folder 32)
    - Job Segregation, 1980 (Box 87, Folder 33)
    - Co-ordinated Market Policy (Box 87, Folder 34)
    - Co-ordinated Market Policy, 1976-1986 (Box 87, Folder 35)
    - Co-ordinated Market Policy, 1977-1982 (Box 87, Folder 36)
    - LMPR, 1974-1975 (Box 87, Folder 37)
    - LMPR, 1986-1996 (Box 87, Folder 38)
    - LMPR, 1977-1995 (Box 87, Folder 39)
    - LMPR, 1975-1985 (Box 87, Folder 40)
    - LMPR, 1974-1997 (Box 87, Folder 41)
    - LMPR, 1995 (Box 87, Folder 42)
    - LMPR (Box 87, Folder 43)
    - LMPR - EC, 1977-1980 (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - LMPR - EC, 1980 (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - LMPR - EC, 1968-1982 (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - LMPR - EC, 1970-1978 (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - LMPR - Eastern Europe, 1979-1985 (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - LMPR - Eastern Europe, 1990-1996 (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - LMPR - Europe, 1992-1997 (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - LMPR - Multinational - Global Corp. Practice, 1981 (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - LMPR - Nordic Countries, 1976-1985 (Box 88, Folder 9)
    - LMPR - No America, 1988 (Box 88, Folder 10)
    - LMPR - OECD, 1965-1972 (Box 88, Folder 11)
    - LMPR - Re-entry, 1978-1982 (Box 88, Folder 12)
    - LMPR - U.N., 1980 (Box 88, Folder 13)
    - LMPR - wages, 1997 (Box 88, Folder 14)
    - LMPR - White Collar Wkrs., 1978-1985 (Box 88, Folder 15)
    - Law, 1982-1990 (Box 88, Folder 16)
    - Legislation, 1978-1993 (Box 88, Folder 17)
    - Lesbians, gays, 1994 (Box 88, Folder 18)
    - Marriage, 1975 (Box 88, Folder 19)
    - Maternity Leave, 1974-1984 (Box 88, Folder 20)
    - Mexico - NAFTA, 1994 (Box 88, Folder 21)
    - Migrant Wkrs., 1974-1995 (Box 88, Folder 22)
    - Migration, 1996 (Box 88, Folder 23)
    - NAFTA, 1997 (Box 88, Folder 24)
    - Nordic, 1971-1993 (Box 88, Folder 25)
    - Older Wkrs., 1980 (Box 88, Folder 26)
    - Org. for Econ. Coop & Dev., 1975-1994 (Box 88, Folder 27)
    - OECD, 1978 (Box 88, Folder 28)
    - OECD, 1978 (Box 88, Folder 29)
    - Other Services (no date) (Box 88, Folder 30)
    - Pacific Forum, 1997 (Box 88, Folder 31)
    - Pensions, 1990 (Box 88, Folder 32)
    - Politics, 1972-1995 (Box 88, Folder 33)
    - Poverty, 1981 (Box 88, Folder 34)
    - Protective Legislation, 1976-1990 (Box 88, Folder 35)
    - Protective Legislation (no date) (Box 88, Folder 36)
    - Protective Legislation, 1992 (Box 88, Folder 37)
    - Protective Legislation, 1992 (Box 88, Folder 38)
    - Protective Legislation, 1992 (Box 88, Folder 39)
    - Research, 1985-1992 (Box 88, Folder 40)
    - Salaries, 1972 (Box 88, Folder 41)
    - Scandinavia, 1992-1997 (Box 88, Folder 42)
    - Sex Roles, 1974-1975 (Box 88, Folder 43)
    - Sexual Harassment, 1981-1991 (Box 88, Folder 44)
    - Social and Political Change, 1974 (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Social Policy, 1973-1994 (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Social Services (no date) (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - South Asia, 1995 (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Standard of Living, 1976 (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - Support Systems, 1978 (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - Sweden (no date) (Box 89, Folder 7)
    - Taxation and Social Security Law, 1976-1986 (Box 89, Folder 8)
    - Technology, 1986-1987 (Box 89, Folder 9)
    - Theory (no date) (Box 89, Folder 10)
    - Third World, 1983-1985 (Box 89, Folder 11)
    - Trade Union Policy and Practice, 1978-1995 (Box 89, Folder 12)
    - Trade Union Policy and Practice, 1966-1978 (Box 89, Folder 13)
    - Trade Union Policy and Practice - FIET, 1974-1980 (Box 89, Folder 14)
    - Trade Union Policy and Practice - FIET, 1974-1985 (Box 89, Folder 15)
    - Trade Union Policy and Practice - FIET, 1989-1996 (Box 89, Folder 16)
    - Trade Unions - Food Wkrs., 1988-1992 (Box 89, Folder 17)
    - Trade Unions - Germany, 1977-1993 (Box 89, Folder 18)
    - Trade Unions - Germany, 1986-1992 (Box 89, Folder 19)
    - Trade Unions - Germany, 1978-1983 (Box 89, Folder 20)
    - Trade Unions - General, 1975-1984 (Box 89, Folder 21)
    - Trade Unions - ICFTSU, 1980-1996 (Box 89, Folder 22)
    - Trade Unions - IMF, 1975-1993 (Box 89, Folder 23)
    - Trade Unions - Int'l. Metal Wkrs., 1977-1982 (Box 89, Folder 24)
    - Traditional/National Values, 1956-1980 (Box 89, Folder 25)
    - Traditional/National Values, 1975-1978 (Box 89, Folder 26)
    - Traditional/National Values, 1974-1989 (Box 89, Folder 27)
    - Traditional/National Values, 1976-1979 (Box 89, Folder 28)
    - Traditional/National Values, 1976-1979 (Box 89, Folder 28)
    - Unemployment, 1978-1986 (Box 89, Folder 29)
    - Unemployment, 1979 (Box 89, Folder 30)
    - United Nations, 1975-1985 (Box 89, Folder 31)
    - United Nations, 1986-1992 (Box 89, Folder 32)
    - United Nations, 1992-1997 (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - United Nations, 1970-1975 (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - United Nations, 1971-1975 (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - United Nations, 1971-1973 (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - United Nations, 1974 (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - United Nations - Conferences, 1995-1997 (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - United Nations - Council in the Status of Women, 1978-1980 (Box 90, Folder 7)
    - UNESCO, 1993 (Box 90, Folder 8)
    - United Nations - Nairobi, 1986 (Box 90, Folder 9)
    - United Nations - Naroibi, 1985-1986 (Box 90, Folder 10)
    - United Nations - Naroibi, 1985 (Box 90, Folder 11)
    - U.S. and Africa, 1997 (Box 90, Folder 12)
    - US and UK, 1990 (Box 90, Folder 13)
    - US and USSR, 1997 (Box 90, Folder 14)
    - Vocational Training, 1982-1985 (Box 90, Folder 15)
    - Vocational Training, 1984-1985 (Box 90, Folder 16)
    - Vocational Training, 1985-1991 (Box 90, Folder 17)
    - Vocational Training, 1970-1989 (Box 90, Folder 18)
    - Wages, 1979-1995 (Box 90, Folder 19)
    - Women, 1972-1975 (Box 90, Folder 20)
    - Women - Economics, 1975 (Box 90, Folder 21)
    - Women's Liberation, 1973 (Box 90, Folder 22)
    - Women's Orgs., 1977-1987 (Box 90, Folder 23)
    - World Trade Union Conf., 1972 (Box 90, Folder 24)
    - Women's Orgs., 1977-1987 (Box 90, Folder 25)
    - Works Councils, 1996 (Box 90, Folder 26)
    - World Bank, 1995-1997 (Box 90, Folder 27)
    - World Employ. Conf., 1976 (Box 90, Folder 28)
  - Sub-Series F. Teachers Study (UFT) Research Files
    - Admin. Comm. Exec. Bd., 1965-1971 (Box 91, Folder 1-8)
    - AFT, 1959-1971 (Box 91, Folder 9-11)
    - Official UFT Chapter Chariman's Handbook, 1975 (Box 91, Folder 12)
    - Bargaining Units, 1966 (Box 91, Folder 13)
    - Chapters UFT, 1964-1971 (Box 91, Folder 14-20)
    - Coll. Barg., 1965-1966 (Box 91, Folder 21-23)
    - Coll. Barg. Higher Educ., 1968-1970 (Box 91, Folder 24)
    - Committees-UFT, 1963-1972 (Box 91, Folder 25-30)
    - General, 1970-1971 (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - Grievance Procedures, 1968 (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - "Last Week at the UFT", 1965-1969 (Box 92, Folder 3-5)
    - Leaflets, 1965-1971 (Box 92, Folder 6-12)
    - Local 1484, 1965 (Box 92, Folder 13)
    - Legislation, 1966 (Box 92, Folder 14)
    - Legislative, 1967-1969 (Box 92, Folder 15)
    - Misc., 1966-1967 (Box 92, Folder 16)
    - Natl. Educ. Assn., 1963-1966 (Box 92, Folder 17)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1967 (Box 92, Folder 18-19)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1968 (Box 92, Folder 20-28)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1969 (Box 92, Folder 29-35)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1968-1969 (Box 93, Folder 1-11)
    - Opposition Staff, 1964-1966 (Box 93, Folder 12)
    - Organizations, 1966 (Box 93, Folder 13)
    - Patchogue, 1965 (Box 93, Folder 14)
    - Philadelphia Teachers, 1965-1968 (Box 93, Folder 15)
    - Reorganization-UFT, 1968 (Box 93, Folder 16)
    - Rochester, 1965 (Box 93, Folder 17)
    - Salaries, 1966-1967 (Box 93, Folder 18-20)
    - Schools Committee, 1967 (Box 93, Folder 21)
    - Shanker, 1969-1972 (Box 93, Folder 22)
    - Staff Manual, 1971 (Box 93, Folder 23)
    - Strike, 1967-1969 (Box 93, Folder 24-27)
    - Table of Contents UFT, 1970 (Box 93, Folder 28)
    - Tenure (Box 93, Folder 29)
    - UFT, 1971-1972 (Box 93, Folder 30-39)
    - UFT Basic Documents, 1965-1966 (Box 94, Folder 1)
    - UFT Officer Interviews, 1966 (Box 94, Folder 2-4)
    - Universities and Colleges, 1956-1972 (Box 94, Folder 5-12)
    - Universities and Colleges, 1965-1966 (Box 94, Folder 13)
    - Urban Community, 1961 (Box 94, Folder 14)
  - Sub-Series G. Working Mothers
    - Australia Interviews I and II, 1973 (Box 95, Folder 1-2)
    - Australia Corresp., 1973-1974 (Box 95, Folder 3-4)
    - Austria, 1973-1975 (Box 95, Folder 5)
    - Canada, 1974 (Box 95, Folder 6)
    - China Interviews I and II, 1969-1973 (Box 95, Folder 7-8)
    - Cuba Corresp. And Interviews, 1964-1972 (Box 95, Folder 9)
    - Cuba Supplemental Material, 1964-1974 (Box 95, Folder 10-11)
    - England, 1975 (Box 95, Folder 12)
    - Finland, 1974 (Box 95, Folder 13)
    - Germany East Interviews, 1972-1973 (Box 95, Folder 14)
    - Germany East Corresp., 1972-1973 (Box 95, Folder 15)
    - Germany West Interviews, 1973 (Box 95, Folder 16-20)
    - Germany West Corresp., 1972-1975 (Box 95, Folder 21)
    - Israel Interviews I and II, 1972 (Box 95, Folder 22-23)
    - Israel Corresp., 1972-1973 (Box 95, Folder 24)
    - Israel Notes, 1972-1973 (Box 95, Folder 25)
    - Japan Corresp. etc, 1972-1973 (Box 95, Folder 26-27)
    - Japan Nakamoto, 1979-1981 (Box 95, Folder 28)
    - Japan Interviews I and II, 1973 (Box 95, Folder 29-32)
    - Korea, 1972 (Box 95, Folder 33)
    - Norway (Box 95, Folder 34)
    - Poland, 1972 (Box 95, Folder 35)
    - Puerto Rico, 1973 (Box 95, Folder 36)
    - Rumania, 1972-1973 (Box 95, Folder 37-38)
    - Russia Corresp., 1972-1973 (Box 95, Folder 39)
    - Russia Misc., 1972-1973 (Box 95, Folder 40)
    - Sweden Corresp., 1972 (Box 96, Folder 1)
    - Sweden Interviews, 1972 (Box 96, Folder 2-4)
    - Sweden Misc., 1972 (Box 96, Folder 5)
    - General and Comparative, 1972-1975 (Box 96, Folder 6)
    - Ford Contracts and Corresp., 1972-1974 (Box 96, Folder 7)
    - Int'l Orgs., 1972-1975 (Box 96, Folder 8)
    - Outlines for Countries Visited (Box 96, Folder 9)
    - Publication General, 1972-1973 (Box 96, Folder 10)
    - Women's Studies, 1973 (Box 96, Folder 11)
    - Women Speaking, 1972-1973 (Box 96, Folder 12)
  - Sub-Series H. Public Sector
    - City-State, 1963-1969 (Box 97, Folder 1-11)
    - Federal, 1955-1970 (Box 97, Folder 12-15)
    - Foreign, 1966-1971 (Box 97, Folder 16)
    - Interviews, Notes, Reports, 1958-1969 (Box 98, Folder 1-6)
    - Manuscript Drafts, 1969 (Box 98, Folder 7-8)
    - Misc., 1958-1971 (Box 98, Folder 9-16)
    - Police Strike NYC, 1971 (Box 98, Folder 17-18)
    - Politics NY, 1968-1969 (Box 98, Folder 19)
    - State County Constitution, 1964 (Box 98, Folder 20-22)
    - Teachers, 1963-1971 (Box 98, Folder 23-27)
    - Transport, 1959-1965 (Box 98, Folder 28)
    - Welfare, 1966-1967 (Box 98, Folder 29)
  - Sub-Series I. Local Union Governments
    - Local Union Govts "Plan of Study" (Box 99, Folder 1)
    - Local 3, 1959-1961 (Box 99, Folder 2-4)
    - Local 6 Notes and Interviews, 1960-1962 (Box 99, Folder 5)
    - Local 6 Manuscript Drafts, 1959-1960 (Box 99, Folder 6-10)
    - Local 6 Misc, 1957-1960 (Box 99, Folder 11-12)
    - Local 32b, 1941-1962 (Box 99, Folder 13-14)
    - Local 56 Misc, 1956-1960 (Box 99, Folder 15)
    - Dist. 65 Notes Interviews, 1959-1960 (Box 99, Folder 16-17)
    - Dist. 65 Manuscript Drafts, 1959 (Box 99, Folder 18)
    - Dist. 65 Misc., 1952-1961 (Box 99, Folder 19-22)
    - Index Cards Dist. 65, 1935-1962 (Box 99, Folder 23)
    - Index Cards Local 3, 6, 32b, 1951-1962 (Box 99, Folder 24)
    - Index Cards Local 6, 1939-1962 (Box 99, Folder 25-26)
  - Sub-Series J. Equal Pay
    - Corresp., 1975 (Box 100, Folder 1-2)
    - Australia, 1945 (Box 100, Folder 3)
    - Austria, 1972-1974 (Box 100, Folder 4)
    - Canada, 1972 (Box 100, Folder 5)
    - Germany, 1942-1973 (Box 100, Folder 6-7)
    - Great Britain, 1961-1971 (Box 100, Folder 8)
    - Int'l and Comp, 1963-1974 (Box 100, Folder 9)
    - Israel, 1969-1973 (Box 100, Folder 10)
    - Japan, 1961-1972 (Box 100, Folder 11)
    - Norway, 1971 (Box 100, Folder 12)
    - Sweden, 1970 (Box 100, Folder 13)
    - USSR, 1970-1972 (Box 100, Folder 14-15)
    - United States, 1942-1975 (Box 100, Folder 16-21)
    - Chapter Four Draft Child Care, 1975 (Box 100, Folder 22)
    - Australia Child Care (Box 100, Folder 23)
    - Austria Child Care (Box 100, Folder 24)
    - Israel Child Care (Box 100, Folder 25)
    - Japan Child Care (Box 100, Folder 26)
    - Sweden Child Care (Box 100, Folder 27)
    - Manuscript Draft One Master Copy, 1975 (Box 100, Folder 28-30)
    - Manuscript Draft Two Misc., 1975 (Box 100, Folder 31-32)
    - Manuscript Draft Three Manuscript (Box 100, Folder 33-35)
    - Misc., 1975 (Box 100, Folder 36-37)
- Series Series VII: Publications and Writings
  - Sub-Series A. Publications
    - Cook, Alice H. Adaptations of Union Structure for Municipal Collective Bargaining. (Box 101, Folder 1)
      New York School of Industrial and Labor Relations: Cornell University, Ithaca NY. no. 198
    - "After Ten years; A Backward Look at an Education", 1961 (Box 101, Folder 2)
      Unpublished Report. Adult Education in Bavaria, December 1961.
    - "Alice Cook: Life-long Scholar, Consummate Teacher.", 1996 (Box 101, Folder 3)
      Page 46-50 in The ILR School at Fifty, edited by Elaine Gruenfeld Goldberg. NY: Cornell University, 1996.
    - Cook, Alice. "An American Report.", 1966 (Box 101, Folder 4)
      The American Labor Review (August 1966): 27-34?. (Published in Japanese)
    - Cook, Alice H., and Sapakie, Alan L. Annual Report of the Cornell University Ombudsman., 1970 (Box 101, Folder 5)
      Cornell University, June 1970
    - Cook, Alice H., and Sapakie, Alan L. Annual Report of the Cornell University Ombudsman., 1971 (Box 101, Folder 6)
      Cornell University, June 1971
    - Cook, Alice H., Professor Emerita. To Members of the New York State Select Committee on Industrial and Labor Problems., 1974 (Box 101, Folder 7)
      16-Oct-74
    - "Challenges in Managing the New Diverse Labor Force.", 1997 (Box 101, Folder 8)
      Unpublished Report
    - Cook, Alice Hanson. Labor and the Community., 1955 (Box 101, Folder 9)
      New York; State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Cornell University, September 1, 1955.
    - "Comparable Worth: Developments in Selected States.", 1983 (Box 101, Folder 10)
      Chapter in Comparable Worth and Pay Equity, Edited by Helen Remick. Philadelphia: Temple University Press, 1983.
    - Cook, Alice H. Comparable Worth: Developments in Selected States, 1983 (Box 101, Folder 10)
      New York; Center for Women in Government, Autumn 1983.
    - "Comparable Worth Implementation.", 1956 (Box 101, Folder 11)
    - "Current State of Comparable Worth in the United States.", 1990 (Box 101, Folder 12)
    - Cook, Alice H. "Development of Union Interest in Medical Programs.", 1960 (Box 101, Folder 13)
      Industrial Medicine and Surgery Volume 29 Number 2 (February 1960): 73-77.
    - Cook, Alice H. Dual Government in Unions: a Tool for Analysis., 1962 (Box 101, Folder 14)
      New York: State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Cornell University. Originally Published in Industrial and Labor Relations Review, Vol. 15, No. 3, April 1962.
    - Cook, Alice H. "The Disjuncture Between Family and Work.", 1988 (Box 101, Folder 15)
      Review of Families and Work by Naomi Gerstel and Harriet Engel Gross, Women, Households and the Economy, ed. Lourdes Beneria, and ed. Catherine R. Simpson, Spouse, Parent, Worker: On Gender and Multiple Roles, ed. Faye J. Crosby, Managing Success: High Echelon Careers and Motherhood, by Aasta S. Lubin, Remaking Motherhood: How Working Mothers are Shaping our Children's Future, by Anita Shreve, More Equal than Others: Women and Men in Dual Career Marriages, by Rosanna Hertz. Women's Review of Books, 15 July, 1988.
    - Cook, Alice Hanson. "Education of Workers for Public Responsibility in Community and Political Affairs.", 1960 (Box 101, Folder 16)
      Labor's Public Responsibility, NILE Symposium. National Institute of Labor Education. Madison, Wisconsin.
    - Cook, Alice H. Equal Pay: A Multinational History and Comparison, 1975 (Box 101, Folder 17-19)
      NY: Cornell University
    - Cook, Alice H. "Equal Pay: Where is it?", 1975 (Box 101, Folder 20)
      Excerpt from Industrial Relations: A Journal of Economy & Society. Vol. 14, No.2. May 1975. 158-177.
    - Cook, Alice H. "Equal Pay: Where is it?", 1974 (Box 101, Folder 20)
      Eastern Economic Association Meeting. Albany New York; October 26- 27, 1974.
    - Cook, Alice H. "The Effects on the Structure of Society of the Growing Number of Women in the Work Force.", 1979 (Box 101, Folder 21)
      College Board National Forum. October 30, 1979.
    - Cook, Alice H. "Equality in the Workplace: The Role of Trade Unions in Market Economics." (Box 101, Folder 22)
      NY; Cornell University School of Industrial and Labor Relations.
    - Experience Abroad in Reentry and Training (Box 101, Folder 23)
    - Cook, Alice H. "Facts and Conclusions on Adaptations in New York State: Examples of Reality." (Box 101, Folder 24)
    - Cook, Alice H. "Family and Work: Challenges to Labor, Management, and Government.", 1987 (Box 101, Folder 25)
      Relations Industielles, Vol. 42, No. 3, 1987.
    - "Report of a Project at the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Cornell University.", 1966 (Box 101, Folder 26)
      United States. House of Representatives. Subcommittee of the Committee on Government Operations. The Federal Research and Development Programs: The Decisionmaking Process. 89th Congress, 2nd session. Washington
    - Cook, Alice H. "Feminization of Poverty- II.", 1983 (Box 101, Folder 27)
      Outline of a speech given in Ithaca NY, December 9, 1983.
    - Cook, Alice H. "Higher Education and Labor Relations.", 1975 (Box 101, Folder 28)
      December 3, 1975.
    - Cook, Alice H. "The International Labor Organization and Japanese Politics.", 1965 (Box 101, Folder 29)
      Reprinted from Industrial and Labor Relations Review. Vol. 19, No. 1, October 1965.
    - Cook, Alice H. The ILO and Japanese Politics, II: Gain or Loss for Labor?", 1969 (Box 101, Folder 30)
      NY: Cornell University. Reprinted from Industrial and Labor Relations Review. Vol. 22, No. 3. April 1969.
    - Cook, Alice H. The ILO and Japanese Politics, II: Gain or Loss for Labor?", 1969 (Box 101, Folder 30)
      Reprint Series No. 263. NY: Cornell University
    - Cook, Dr. Alice. "Impact of Affirmative Action on Women at Work.", 1979 (Box 101, Folder 31)
      Conference on Rights and Affirmative Action Awareness. East West Center, Honolulu, Hawaii. March 17, 1979.
    - Cook, Alice H., Wohlking, Wallace L. "Increasing Labor participation in Community Affairs: A Report on a Two-Year Demonstration Project in Adult Education for Members of Labor Unions.", 1955 (Box 101, Folder 32)
      New York: Cornell University, January 1955.
    - Cook, Alice H. "Draft of a Policy on the Role of the New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations in it's Conduct of the Project on 'Increasing Labor participation in Community Affairs.'", 1954 (Box 101, Folder 33)
      New York: Cornell University
    - Cook, Alice Hauson. "Arbeiterbildung in den USA.", 1950 (Box 101, Folder 33)
      Bildungsarbeit. November 1950. 81-84.
    - "International Comparisons: Problems and Research in the Industrialized World.", 1987 (Box 101, Folder 34)